So far, we've created two different models.
到目前为止 我们创建了两个不同的模型
The XGBoost model and a linear model.
分别是 XGBoost 模型和线性模型
Suppose now that we wanted to switch from a deployed XGBoost model,
假设我们想从部署的 XGBoost 模型切换到
to a new linear model.
新的线性模型
However, we want to make sure that our new model is performing
但是 我们希望新模型的性能
at least close enough to our XGBoost model.
至少与 XGBoost 模型很接近
One of the ways we might do this is by performing A-B test, that is,
一种实现方式是执行 A/B 测试
we create a new endpoint that receives a bunch of data,
即创建一个新的端点 端点将接收一堆数据
and then the endpoint decides which of the two models to send that data to.
然后判断将数据发送给两个模型中的哪个模型
We can do that when we set up an endpoint configuration
我们可以在端点配置中进行设置
by listing each model as its own production variant.
分别将每个模型列为生产变体
So here, we're creating a new endpoint configuration,
所以我们将创建新的端点配置
in which we have listed two production variants.
并列出两个生产变体
The first, is the linear model and we give it the name linear model,
第一个是线性模型 命名为 Linear-Model
and the second is the XGBoost model,
第二个是 XGBoost 模型
whose name is XGB-Model.
命名为 XGB-Model
The amount of data that the endpoint will send to
端点发送给每个模型的数据量
each model is dependent on the initial variant weight.
取决于 InitialVariantWeight
The way that SageMaker determines the proportion of data to send each model,
为了确定发送给每个模型的数据比例
is that it will take a total of all of the weights,
SageMaker 将计算权重总和
and then it will say the proportion of data that I send to the first model,
然后 发送给第一个模型的数据比例是
will be that model's weight,
该模型的权重
divided by the total,
除以权重总和
and it will perform a similar calculation for each of the other production variants.
并对其他生产变体分别执行相似的计算流程
In this case, we have two models,
我们有两个模型
each of which has weight one.
每个模型的权重是 1
So the total is two,
所以总和是 2
which means that one over two or half of the data will be sent to
1/2 的数据将发送给线性模型
the linear model and the other half of the data will be sent to the XGBoost model.
另一半数据将发送给 XGBoost 模型
Once we've created that endpoint configuration,
创建了端点配置后
we can of course ask SageMaker to create an endpoint with those properties.
就要求 SageMaker 用这些属性创建端点
So our endpoint is up and running,
端点现在已经在运行
and we can send some data to it.
我们可以向其发送一些数据
So as we've been doing so far,
按照之前的操作
we will start by sending just the first row of
在序列化数据后 首先将测试数据集的
our test dataset after we serialize it to this new combined endpoint.
第一行发送给新的组合端点
In the response, we can see that our data was sent to the XGBoost model.
在响应中可以看到数据发送给了 XGBoost 模型
Next, let's take a look at sending the first 10 rows of our test dataset to the endpoint,
下面将测试数据集的前 10 行发送给端点
and print out the response from each of those calls.
并输出每个调用的响应
We can see that the first one was sent to the XGBoost model,
可以看到第一行发送给了 XGBoost 模型
the next was sent to the linear model,
下一行发送给了线性模型
XGBoost again, XGBoost, linear model, et cetera.
再次发送给XGBoost XGBoost 线性模型 等等
Essentially what SageMaker is doing,
SageMaker 的做法是
is whenever data comes into the endpoint,
每次端点收到数据后
it flips a coin, heads goes to the XGBoost model,
SageMaker 将“投掷硬币” 正面朝上的话 数据发送给 XGBoost 模型
tails goes to the linear model.
反面朝上的话 发送给线性模型
If at some point we forget the configuration of a deployed endpoint,
如果我们忘记了已部署端点的配置
we can use this described endpoint method of the SageMaker client.
可以使用 sagemaker_client 的 describe_endpoint 方法
The return result will be a JSON object or Python dictionary,
返回结果是一个 JSON 对象或 Python 字典
which describes all of the properties that we set about that specific endpoint.
描述了我们对此端点设置的所有属性
This is a little difficult to read,
读起来有点乱
but we can see here that there is an entry for production variants,
但是可以看到这里有个 ProductionVariants 条目
which includes the linear model and the XGBoost model.
其中包含线性模型和 XGBoost 模型
So now suppose we've been running this A-B test for a while,
假设A/B 测试已经运行了一段时间
and we've been collecting data,
我们一直在收集数据
and it turns out that it's working pretty well,
发现证据很可靠
our new linear model is working very well.
新的线性模型效果很不错
So we'd like to complete the change, that is,
我们想完成更改
instead of having our endpoint send data to both the XGBoost model and the linear model,
即不再让端点向 XGBoost 和线性模型发送数据
we'd like to change it so that it only sends data to the linear model.
而是做出更改 只向线性模型发送数据
To do that, we can use the update_endpoint method of the SageMaker Client.
我们可以使用 sagemaker_client 的 update_endpoint 方法
All we have to do, is specify which endpoint we'd like to update,
只需指定要更新哪个端点
and what endpoint configuration we would like
以及更新完毕后
that endpoint to look like once the update has finished.
端点配置使用哪个
In this case we are going to update our previously deployed endpoint,
我们将更新之前部署的端点
so that its configuration only sends data to the linear model.
配置为仅向线性模型发送数据
Of course, this is happening in the background.
当然 这些都在后台发生
In the meantime, if we take a look at the endpoint as it currently exists,
与此同时 我们看看当前存在的端点
we can see that it currently has two production variants,
可以看到 目前有两个生产变体
the linear model and the XGBoost model.
分别是线性模型和 XGBoost 模型
The reason for this is that the endpoint,
原因是
which uses the linear model endpoint configuration,
使用线性模型端点配置的端点
has not yet started,
尚未开始
and SageMaker wants to make sure that our endpoints never go down.
SageMaker 要确保端点从未中断
So in the background,
所以在后台
SageMaker will first launch a new endpoint,
SageMaker 将首先启动新的端点
with the configuration that we want to change our deployed endpoint to.
并具有我们要将部署的端点更改为的配置
Once that new endpoint is ready,
新端点准备好后
it will then configure the existing endpoint so that it routes
它将配置现有端点
all data to the new endpoint that has been created.
使其将所有数据都发送到创建的新端点
This way, the end-user never sees any downtime.
这样的话 最终用户就不会看到中断情况
To see this, let's wait for our endpoint to finish being updated.
为了查看这种情况 我们等待端点更新完毕
Now that our endpoint has been updated so that it only points to the linear model,
端点现已更新为仅指向线性模型
we can ask SageMaker to describe this endpoint,
我们可以要求 SageMaker 描述此端点
and see that indeed,
可以看到
the current endpoint has only a single production variant,
当前端点的确只有一个生产变体
which is the linear model.
即线性模型
Of course, we should make sure to shut down the endpoint now that we're finished with it.
使用完毕后 我们需要关闭端点
So, we looked at how you can create an endpoint that sends data to more than one model,
我们学习了如何创建向多个模型发送数据的端点
and we looked at how you can update an existing endpoint,
并学习了如何更新现有端点
so that there's no loss of service to the end-user.
使用户感受不到服务中断